Guide to the Harold I. Seeley, Jr. Collection on Cherry Grove
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Harold I. Seeley, Jr. collection on Cherry Grove
1924-2011
MS 1908
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
11.33
(18 boxes)
The materials comprise correspondence, meeting minutes, reports, printed ephemera, posters, photographs, and play scripts collected by Harold I. Seeley, Jr. that document the activities of the Arts Project of Cherry Grove, as well as the community of Cherry Grove, a lesbian, gay, bisexual and transgender (LGBT) resort community on Fire Island, off the coast of Long Island, New York.
Seeley, Harold I.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Harold I. Seeley, Jr., 2008-2009.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Harold I. Seeley, Jr. had been a volunteer for Cherry Grove Arts Project activities since his arrival at Cherry Grove in the mid 1970s, donating his time as board member, set designer, and performer. In 1982, Seeley founded the Cherry Grove Archives, collecting materials to preserve the history of the Cherry Grove community and the arts project. He died in Brooklyn, New York, on January 7, 2012.
The Arts Project Cherry Grove (APCG) was founded in 1948 as a non-profit community service organization providing an environment receptive to showcasing various art forms. Its fundraising events include art shows; theater productions; casino and bingo nights; concerts; socials; balls; and membership parties. Monies raised benefit various organizations of Cherry Grove, a hamlet located on Fire Island, New York, and reputedly the nation's first lesbian, gay, bisexual, and transgender/transsexual (LGBT) community.
Scope and Contents
The materials comprise correspondence, meeting minutes, reports, printed ephemera, posters, photographs, and play scripts collected by Harold I. Seeley, Jr. that document the activities of the Arts Project of Cherry Grove, as well as the community of Cherry Grove, a lesbian, gay, bisexual and transgender (LGBT) resort community on Fire Island, off the coast of Long Island, New York.
Community arts projects; Cherry Grove (N.Y.); Fire Island (N.Y.: Island); LGBTQ resource; Seeley, Harold I.; Arts Project Cherry Grove (APCG)
- Inventory, 1958-2006
  - Arts Project of Cherry Grove (APCG)
    - Calendar, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Cherry Grove archives, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Cherry Grove's Art Show, 1984-1985, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Copy of program for Cherry Grove Follies of 1948 (first show), 1989 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Flyers, announcements, clippings, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Minutes, flyers, announcements, 1958-1960, 1980-1989 (Box 1, Folder 7-17)
    - Minutes, flyers, announcements, 1990-1998 (Box 2, Folder 1-8)
    - Notebooks and binders
      - Drach, Ted: minutes, reports, and correspondence, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Fowler, Nat, collection of playbills
        - Playbills, 1960-1974 (Box 2, Folder 10)
        - News/stories, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - Sinisi, Nicholas
        - APCG New York, 1978-1980 (Box 2, Folder 12-16)
        - APCG New York, 1976-1980 (Box 3, Folder 1)
        - Patrons, circa 1980 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Playscripts
      - Baker, David, Red, Hot and Rose, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Baker, David [adaptation], Ruddigore?!!?! or The Curse of the Belvederes!, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Drach, Ted, Grove Fever, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Drach, Ted, Grove Frankenstein, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Stella, Leo, All American Boy, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Posters for Cherry Grove productions, Circa 1980-2002 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Programs, 1979-2006 (Box 3, Folder 8-11)
    - West Side Discussion Group, The West Sider, New York, 1978-1982 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Cherry Grove community
    - Aerial photograph, Undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Civic/Memorial Fund, Inc., 1990-2006 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Community Association, 2002-2006 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Property Owner's Association, Inc., 1981-2002 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Community Theatre, Cherry Grove, Fire Island, 1966-1970 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - The Dunes Fund, Inc., Circa 1981 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Map, Circa 1960s (Box 6)
  - Imperial Court of New York, 2000-2005 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Additional material, 1948-2009; Accession 2009-M-070
  Scope and Contents
  Materials in this accession were taken from both the Cherry Grove Archives and the personal collection of the donor. The materials comprise meeting minutes, reports, printed ephemera, clippings, and photographs that document the activities of the Arts Project of Cherry Grove, as well as the community of Cherry Grove.
  Arrangement
  Arrangement of the materials preserves the distinction between those coming from the Cherry Grove Archives and those coming from Harold Seeley's personal collection. Therein, files are arranged topically, primarily by names of organizations.
  - Cherry Grove Archives
    - Arts Project of Cherry Grove (APCG)
      - By-laws, director's contract, lease, financial records, 1966-1991 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Flyers, 1952-2006 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Fundraisers, ball, membership applications, 1980-2007 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Membership cards, 1978, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Membership list, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Newsletters, correspondence, 1978-2007 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Programs, 1948, 1978-1999 (Box 1, Folder 7-14)
      - Programs, 2000-2008 (Box 2, Folder 1-6)
      - Records
        Material removed from binders or notebooks.
        - Drach, Ted, 1966-1968 (Box 2, Folder 7-8)
          Contains minutes, correspondence, meeting notes, contracts, membership, committee, and board information, and miscellaneous material (flyers, announcements, ballots, petitions).
        - 1975-1988 (Box 3, Folder 1-7)
          Contains minutes, correspondence, and financial information.
      - Show announcements, 2001, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Tickets, 1978, 1999-2003, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Cherry Grove community
      - Glen Boles publicity photograph, autographed, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - Cherry Grove Community Association, Inc. (CGCAI) announcements, fundraising solicitations, 2006-2009 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - Cherry Grove Property Owners' Association (CGPOA)
        - Flyers, announcements, 1995-2000, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
        - Membership cards, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - Ferry service schedules, 1978, 1991-2007 (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
      - Printed ephemera: flyers, ads, map, menu, hotel rates, 1978-2006 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - Taxpayers' Association membership forms, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Wells, Steve: clippings and drafts of articles, 1989-2001 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Harold Seeley material
    - Arts Project of Cherry Grove
      - Flyers, announcements, forms, fundraising, 1981-2008 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - Newsclippings, mostly on Arts Project Archives, 1993-2005 (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - Newsclippings, mostly on Arts Project Archives, 1986-2002 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Notes on the history of the APCG, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 8)
      - Proposal, planning, and script for performance of Jeffrey, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Cherry Grove community
      - Articles from newspapers and magazines, Circa 1960-1993 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - As the Grove Turns newsletter, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - Bayview Services LLC brochure, Undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
      - Fire Island Association
        - Correspondence, brochure, flyers, 2003-2006, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
        - Newsletter, 1999-2008 (Box 4, Folder 13)
      - Fire Island National Seashore: report and trail guide, 2007, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
      - Fowler, Nat, Collection
        - Flyer for memorial service, 1994 August 28 (Box 4, Folder 15)
        - Stories and columns for Fire Island Tide, 1983-1989 (Box 4, Folder 16)
        - Stories and columns for Fire Island Tide, 1983-1989 (Box 5, Folder 1)
        - Newton, Esther, Cherry Grove, Fire Island autographed copy, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 2)
        - Photograph album of Cherry Grove, Undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - Fundraising solicitations, announcements, flyers, photograph, 1987-2007 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - AIDS Walk New York program, 1992 May 31 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Imperial Court of New York: programs, invitations, 1993-2005 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - SAGE (Senior Action in a Gay Environment): newsletters and flyers, 1996-2008 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Additional material, 1924-2011; Accession 2015-M-058
  This accession comprises records of the Arts Project of Cherry Grove (APCG) as well as materials related to the greater Cherry Grove community. Records from APCG include financial records, assistant books and records, and general administrative and project files. Assistant books and records contain board meeting minutes, board meeting agendas, contact information for the Board of Directors, and notes on projects in progress. Financial records include treasurer reports, budgets, and ledger pages. Other records include ephemera from APCG events such as fliers and play programs, correspondence, and files related to specific projects. Materials related to the Cherry Grove community at large include correspondence and documents from other Cherry Grove community organizations, guidebooks to Fire Island, photographs, and newspaper clippings. Materials date from 1924 to 2011, with the bulk from 1951 to the mid-2000s.
  Materials are arranged alphabetically.
  - Arts Project of Cherry Grove
    - General
      - Calendars, 1978-2010 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Cherry Grove Art Project news, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence, 1955-2008 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Fliers, 2010, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Grand inaugural ball, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Minutes, 1955-1956, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Minutes and notes, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1978-1981 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Offering circulars, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Play programs, 1951-2011 (Box 1, Folder 10-12, Box 2, Folder 1-2)
      - Posters, 1966-2011 (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
      - Signed posters, 1989-1995, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Assistant books and records, 1948-2010 (Box 2, Folder 3-9, Box 3, Folder 1-11)
    - Finances, 1948-2008 (Box 3, Folder 12-15, Box 4, Folder 1-7)
  - Cherry Grove community
    - Cherry Grove Civic/Memorial Fund, Circa 2000-2001 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Cherry Grove Community Association, 2002-2007 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Cherry Grove Property Owners Association, 1987-2004 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Cherry Grove rehabilitation, Circa 1924-1955 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Fire Island guides, 1962-1995 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Harold Seeley tributes, 2010-2011 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Newspaper clippings and magazine articles, 2004-2008 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Notes on history of Cherry Grove, Circa 2008 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - "Out on the Island", 1992-1998 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Permanent dunes fund, 1962, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Photographs from Nat Fowl album, 1951-1966 (Box 5, Folder 3-4)
    - Sea shack, beach hotel, and club, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - The Violet Letter, 2010 (Box 5, Folder 6)